Contact

sebastsing@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/sebastian-hellsing-918697136 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Java

SQL

Microsoft Office

Certifications

Oracle Certified Associate, Java SE 8 Programmer

Sebastian Hellsing

Application Developer II

Summary

I am a passionate software developer with years of various IT experience. I am currently working for Essendant building and maintaining full stack Java web apps and APIs. I have a proven history of quickly becoming proficient and a contributing team member with any number of tools. I am a problem solver who keeps the big picture in mind while maintaining laser focus on the small.

Experience

Essendant

1 year 9 months

Application Developer II
June 2018 - Present

Denver, Colorado

I am a part of a partially remote web development team responsible for several customer facing applications and APIs .

I take requirements and turn them into features and enhancements to help drive the core strategy of the organization. Working with that goal in mind, I contribute to a scheduled release cycle for several applications, from sprint planning to production delivery.

Work on these applications routinely involve the full stack of several database flavors, Java EE, and various front-end technologies.

Responsible for providing development support for clients troubleshooting and implementing our commercial APIs and web widgets.

Application Developer
July 2017 - May 2018 (11 months)

Greater Denver Area

I am part of a team responsible for enhancing and maintaining several web applications and APIs. I take requirements and turn them into working features

and fix defects in existing ones. The work spans across the full web stack including but not limited to: AngularJS, Java and Oracle/SQL Server.

Primary Responsibilities

Design, Code & Test across the full web stack Interpret business requirements and turn them into working features.

Manage code changes across multiple projects and repositories.

Provide estimates and dependency information for completion of work.

Collaborate with internal and external teams
Participate in daily scrums and other agile meetings.

Self-Employed Java Developer June 2016 - July 2017 (1 year 2 months) Florida

Full Stack Java Developer working on contract basis.

Developed Java applications to manage active directory users (unlock accounts, add/remove from groups, etc) with Angular front end.

Meridian Asset Services System Administrator September 2016 - April 2017 (8 months)

Tampa/St. Petersburg, Florida Area

- Managed information systems for financial company with 120 internal users, 300+ external users, and 30+ servers, including public facing webservers that drives the core product of the company.
- Utilized my knowledge of PowerShell to automate many routine tasks, allowing the IT team to allot time to more productive items.
- Restructured inefficient Active Directory to allow for better account and group policy management.
- Configured Domain Controllers and DNS to allow for 2-way authentication for trusted domains.
- Configured SonicWALL firewall for SSL VPN access for users, as well as site-to-site VPNS connecting remote locations.

• Created and implemented written IT Security policies to increase the organization's security posture.

Engineered Management Solutions System Administrator May 2016 - September 2016 (5 months) Greater Memphis Area

EMS is a small IT firm providing relevant services to businesses across the Memphis area. Support was provided for more than 40 client businesses with more than 700 PCs (Windows, and OS Mac) and 120 servers with various networked peripherals.

- Responsible for setup and support for exchange/hosted mail services.
- Building and configuring servers(including MS server 2008-2012 and SBS)
- Break fix for everyday client users.
- Maintenance of client Active Directory and group policy.
 Maintenance of network and cloud based backups.

Freedom Federal Credit Union
Network System Administrator
December 2014 - December 2015 (1 year 1 month)
Aberdeen, Maryland

- Tooracon, maryland
- Responsible for the maintenance and support of all infrastructure and banking support systems. This includes end user support and the installation, maintenance and support of computers, servers, software, peripherals, telecommunications equipment, firewalls, network switches, routers, intrusion detection equipment, cabling, systems monitoring, and backup and recovery.
- Configured, administered, and maintained Windows servers2008/2012, Active Directory, and Exchange.
- Maintained user IDs and application access control lists. Systems and network security, including server patch management, risk reduction and antivirus.
- Created and built desktops to user's required criteria. Creating and deploying system images for Windows XP/7/8/10, Mac OSX, IOS and Android mobile devices.

United States Marine Corps System Administrator October 2009 - July 2014 (4 years 10 months) Washington, DC Pentagon

- Duties included desktop, VTC, Blackberry, and VOIP support approx. 170 users
- The creation and management of network accounts
- Managing hardware replacement, upgrades, and adjusting resources for changing budgets.
- Software procurement, installation, and support through successful deployments.
- Daily work in an Active directory environment
- Familiar with Link, Microsoft office suites, and Adobe pro/creative suites
- Remote desktop and VNC remote control software
- Incudes the physical security of IT equipment and office spaces where they are stored or contained.
- Responsibilities included physical security of classified office space,
 personnel security, maintenance of security clearances, various IT support.
- Maintaining and controlling access to office spaces
- Experience with imaging software, and OS configuration to meet requirements stated in the appropriate guidance.
- Ensured the operability of IT hardware and software for 60+ users, to include desktops, laptops, blackberries, and each user's individual software needs.
- Managed network resources utilizing Cisco routers and switches.
- Experience with disaster recovery and backup (on-site and off-site) of information.

Education

Skill Distillery

Computer Programming · (2017 - 2017)